i enjoyed gigantic bowls of cereal every
morning as a kid but that added up to
hundreds and hundreds of calories and
one chubby little boy in today's video i
will transform the milk and cereal we
know and love into a low calorie scrum
scoopable treat that you can eat every
day without worrying about packing on
the pounds the best part they are just
as good as its halo top counterpart for
half the calories let's get into it we
will start with our pint on a scale we
will then weigh out 160 grams of one
percent fair life milk 280 grams of
almond milk and 4.2 grams of vanilla
extract if you are having trouble
finding one percent fair life you can
buy a half gallon of fat free and a half
gallon of two percent and combine the
two like i did to make this video but
nick can we just use all almond milk
instead you can do that but the quality
of your product becomes extremely
diminished and you will get a lot more
ice crystal formation in your ice cream
during my testing process i try to find
that perfect balance of real milk to
almond milk ratio that kept it as low
calorie as possible without losing that
actual creamy soft ice cream texture
what about only using fat-free milk you
may be surprised but the little bit of
fat in one percent milk actually goes a
long way and again helps keep ice
crystals from forming plus it is only an
extra 14 calories and the improvement in
texture and taste is worth it i promise
then in a separate bowl we will add 50
grams of pure cane 1.5 grams of cinnamon
1 gram of salt and 1 gram xanthan gum
okay do we really need the xanthan gum
now absolutely this is the most
important ingredient of all of them it
helps keep ice crystals from forming
while the ice cream is freezing
especially when using almond milk
because if you didn't know almond milk
is essentially water the xanthan gum
gives the ice cream a much smoother
creamier and overall improved
consistency plus if you buy a bag it
will last you a year if not more
speaking of it is highly important to
have a very accurate scale because
having 1 gram of xanthan gum and having
1.7 grams of xanthan gum can completely
change your finished product personally
i would get one that weighs down to the
0.1 the one i use has been through hell
and back still works perfectly and
costed less than twenty dollars so i
highly recommend it i will put anything
i use in this video in the description
below back to the recipe using your hand
blender of choice i personally like this
little whisk blender thingy i got from
pe science start pouring the dry
ingredients into your pint of wet
ingredients try to mix as slow as
possible to not create too much foam
which will cause the pint to overflow
but fast enough to make sure everything
gets combined without clumping i like to
make sure the mixer is all the way at
the bottom of the pint which prevents
foaming that will lead to overflowing
after all the dry ingredients are mixed
in you will notice the liquid has become
thicker and easier to mix without
creating additional foam at the top once
everything is mixed together blend for
another 90 seconds this will make sure
all of the dry ingredients are dissolved
so that you don't have a majority of
your sweetener and cinnamon sitting at
the bottom of your pint until you get
the hang of it and or to prevent
overflow you can follow all the same
steps in a taller and wider vessel and
blend it in there you still shouldn't
mix on a high speed though because once
you have to transfer it over to the pint
you will still have spillage because of
all the froth formation that formed
above the milk now put the top on your
pint and put it in the freezer for 24
hours yes i know that is a long time to
wait but if you order enough pints for
your creamy you will only have to wait
24 hours once and never have to worry
about waiting again for example right
now i have two more pints of ice cream
as well as several of my 100 calorie
sorbet recipes waiting for me in the
freezer this means i will never have to
live 24 hours without ice cream again
that being said let's blend some up take
your pine out of the freezer and run it
under warm water for 40 seconds but nick
do you have to run it i promise you guys
everything i do i do for a specific
reason i try to keep it as simple as i
can while maintaining the highest
quality recipes as humanly possible i
have learned a lot with the 50 plus
recipes i have done so far and anything
that may seem a little odd or takes a
little extra effort is definitely worth
it dry off the outside of your pint pop
the top off and lock it into place run
the creamy on the ice cream setting and
while that does its thing let's weigh
out the cereal a little cereal goes a
long way so for this we only need 10
grams of cinnamon toast crunch or if you
are like me just use the generic version
because it tastes the same and is way
cheaper after that is weighed out our
first spin should be done one re-spin is
always required but this is how we are
looking after the first spin pretty good
but the re-spin takes the texture to the
next level load it back up and hit that
re-spin button once done re-spinning we
will take a butter knife and try to make
a hole down the middle the diameter of
the knife or just a touch wider if it
looks like this then it is time to fill
that hole up with our delicious cinnamon
toast crunch 10 grams should fit
perfectly to the top of the pint load
your pint back up use the mixing
function and let the creamy work its
magic now i'm sure you were all asking
what should you do with the ice cream on
the knife i suggest you try the
luxurious smooth texture until you have
a full pint of it filled with cinnamon
toast crunch after you unload your pint
it is time to enjoy while we move on to
our second cream with our pint on the
scale we will add 160 grams of one
percent milk 280 grams of almond milk
and 4.2 grams of vanilla extract i would
like to add vanilla extract as a must
for these recipes in my opinion when
baking or making something that is
heated up i would say using imitation
vanilla could possibly work however for
ice cream i think the real vanilla
extract is crucial if you want a true
vanilla ice cream flavor in your final
product at 4.2 grams of vanilla per pint
you can make about 53 pints of ice cream
with an 8 ounce bottle now in a separate
bowl we will add 45 grams of pure cane 1
gram of salt and 1 gram of xanthan gum
mix those until well combined then
slowly add your dry ingredients with
your blender of choice once everything
is combined mix for another 90 seconds
because we want to make sure all the dry
ingredients don't end up sitting at the
bottom of the pine put it in the freezer
and 24 hours later you are ready to
blend run the base of the pint under
water for 40 seconds dry it off and then
load it into your creamy hit that ice
cream button and let it process another
process is weight loss fortunately after
10 years of trying many different diets
and training programs and having my
master's degree in exercise science i
have grown to know what actually works
when it comes to losing weight and
gaining muscle both the experience and
knowledge has laid my foundation as a
fitness coach if you are looking to
upgrade your physique in 2023 and would
like a plan tailored specifically to you
click the link in the description below
once the creamy is done doing its thing
immediately follow up with a respin
while that's going weigh out 11 grams of
lucky charms then unload your pint grab
your knife make a tornado looking hole
in the middle and load it up with your
cereal for this ice cream i like to
leave a few marshmallows and charms on
the side to top this with many of the
pieces get broken down very small and i
like to have some bigger size chunks in
my bites of ice cream grab a spoon and
enjoy for the final cream we will weigh
out 160 grams of milk 265 grams of
almond milk and 4.2 grams of vanilla
extract however this time we have a
secret ingredient fruity pebbles syrup
this syrup tastes exactly like the
colorful cereal itself and for just 15
grams of it your ice cream will taste
like the milk after you just ate a bowl
of fruity pebbles which is
delicious in a separate bowl add 40
grams of pure cane 1 gram of salt and 1
gram of xanthan gum and mix together add
your wet and dry ingredients similar to
the first two recipes throw a cap on it
and put it in the freezer when you're
ready to eat grab your pint rinse it for
40 seconds and throw it in the creamy
hit that ice cream button and when
finished respin it weigh out nine grams
of fruity pebbles and make a hole in the
middle of your ice cream fill that hole
with the fruity pebbles and leave two
grams off to the side load the pint one
last time and use the mix-in setting
once finished top with your remaining
fruity pebbles again this adds more
depth and texture in your ice cream
leading to an overall better eating
experience no matter which one of these
pints you choose to make you will not be
disappointed they are bursting with
flavor have a real ice cream consistency
and only take two minutes of your time
to make grab a cone scoop some ice cream
and while you're eating it you can check
out these hundred calorie sorbets that
are just as easy to make and are equally
delicious in their own right until next
time deuces